A Guide to the Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel Collection of Shenandoah Valley Menus, 1967-1991: SC 0289
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel Collection of Shenandoah Valley Menus,
1967-1991
Special Collections, James Madison University
Whetzel, Marie Catherine Coffman "Nutty", 1919-2019
SC 0289
.2 cubic feet; 16 folders
The Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel Collection of Shenandoah Valley Menus, 1967-1991, primarily comprises menus from Lloyd's Steak House in Harrisonburg, Virginia as well as menus from other local restaurants.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisitioni Information
This collection was acquired from Rolling Hills Antique Mall in Harrisonburg in March 2019.
Provenance
The materials in this collection were sold on March 23, 2019 by Bowman Auctions in Harrisonburg as part of the Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel estate. Whetzel waitressed at several local restaurants over the course of her life.
Bio/Historical Note
Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel (1919-2019) was a waitress at several local restaurants over the course of her life including Garbers Restaurant (Timberville), Belle Meade (Harrisonburg), Pano's (Harrisonburg), and Lloyd's Steak House (Harrisonburg). She resided in Timberville and was active in many community organizations, particularly the street rodding groups Valley Cruisers and Weekend Warriors.
Lloyd's Steak House opened in 1968 by Lloyd and Ruby Newland at 2455 South Main Street in Harrisonburg. The Newlands also operated Southern Kitchen in New Market. The site of Lloyd's was originally a Howard Johnson's restaurant. Lloyd's officially ceased operations on December 31, 1997.
Scope and Content
The Marie Coffman "Nutty" Whetzel Collection of Shenandoah Valley Menus, 1967-1991, primarily comprises menus from Lloyd's Steak House in Harrisonburg, Virginia as well as menus from other local restaurants.
The Lloyd's Steak House menus date from 1983-1991 and include breakfast, lunch, dinner, children's, and cocktail menus. Menus from the Howard Johnson's restaurant in Harrisonburg and the Country Store in Weyers Cave are included. Many of the menus are dated according to handwritten inscriptions.
The collection also includes two programs for the Friends of Feathers group and an auction catalogue for a sale at MD's Chicken in the Rough in New Market.
Arrangement
The menus are arranged according to type and date.
Separated Material
A copy of Building for Christ: Step by Step, the Peoples Church (1950) was separated from the collection and cataloged.
Bibliography
"City Landmark to Close," Daily News-Record, December 30, 1997.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Menus -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- 20th century; Menus -- Virginia -- Rockingham County -- 20th century; Restaurants -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- 20th century; Restaurants -- Virginia -- Rockingham County -- 20th century
Genre and Form Terms:
Menus; Programs (documents)
- Friends of Feathers programs, 1967, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lloyd's Steak House menu, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lunch at Lloyd's menu, November 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lunch at Lloyd's menus, July 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lloyd's Steak House menu, July 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lloyd's Steak House menu, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lunch at Lloyd's menu, March 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- MD's Chicken in the Rough auction sale catalogue (Heatwole Auction Team), February 7, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lloyd's Steak House menu, April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lloyd's Steak House menu, August 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lloyd's Steak House breakfast menu, November 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lloyd's Steak House cocktails, mixed drinks, and wines menu, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lloyd's Steak House menus, napkin, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lloyd's Steak House Kiddies Korner menu, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Country Store menu, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Howard Johnson's menu, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)